[car revving] [upbeat music]
This is a Porsche 911 GT3,
and this car just so happens to be mine.
But I wanted to make a point,
and you're either going to think
that I'm a dickhead
showing off,
or it could just get you thinking.
The average Australian earns just over
100,000 Australian dollars each year.
The tax payable on
that would be about $22,971,
leaving you with $75,044.
But the average Australian spends
about $25,000 a year on rent,
$3,000 a year on utilities,
$8,000 a year on groceries, and
when you add transport, health
insurance, spending,
and typical saving contributions, your
total annual bills
are about $55,000 a year.
Which means the average Australian could
potentially save about
$19,554 each year. But before
comparing that to the car,
let's look at the average property price
in
Australia. As of the latest data,
the national median house price is
approximately 1,009,000 Australian
dollars.
And in Sydney, the median house price
is about 1,482,000.
So for a 20% deposit,
it would take you 10 years of saving to
purchase a house,
or 15 years of saving to purchase a house
in Sydney.
And if they wanted to save money to buy
this car, it would take them 23
years.
I don't think enough people
are talking about the dangers of living an
average
life.
Because I very much doubt you'd be
watching this video if that's what you
wanted.
And this isn't a video where you walk past
a homeless person and go, "Oh,
you're poor." It's more so to wake you up
to the fact that if you don't want to
live an average life
and you want to have an exceptional life,
which you should be
able to have. If you want to wake up
and go,
"I want more money than I know what to
do with.
I want to be able to drive an expensive
car, and I want to fly laying down
on a plane." That is your prerogative,
and you should absolutely be able to do
that. Will it be easy? Probably not.
Will it happen in the next year?
I highly doubt it.
But we live in the most opportunistic age
ever before.
Quite literally, using an iPhone
and probably using a laptop,
you can create a life
for yourself if you do the work.
And I truly believe
that escaping average has
never been easier.
We live in a society where we seem to
think that life is a
zero-sum game. For me to earn good money,
other people must be poor as a
byproduct of it. If I've got money,
I've obviously taken it out the pockets of
other people.
And in British culture especially,
there is this
anti-entrepreneurial vibe. In Australia,
you've got tall poppy syndrome,
where if you had a line of poppies,
the tallest one gets cut down.
People don't actually like to see you do
well.
And on the road to success, people
are just going to try and tear you down.
You can't even lose weight without your
fat mates getting angry about it.
"Oh, Sally,
she got a bit carried away." 20 years ago,
it would be near
impossible for anyone to be able to start
a business or a side hustle or a
hobby or to build a following.
But nowadays, you just need social media.
And that can seem reductive,
but as long as you use it right, you can
surpass average very fast
and fast-track yourself to the top.
Not 1% of earners, but 0.1% of earners.
And in the next few minutes,
I'm going to give you the blueprint to
exactly how you
do that. First thing you should try
and do is grow a following.
I didn't say a massive following,
but a following.
You need a diehard subset of people
that will buy your shit when you sell it.
Now, some people worry, "Oh,
what product am I going to sell?
How much it's going to be?" Worrying about
that before you have a following
is like going, "Hmm,
how am I going to decorate the bedrooms in
my five-bedroom
house?" Which you can't afford yet.
It's like people worrying about flipping
loose skin when they've still got 20
stone to lose. Whatever profession you
are in, you should be able to solve
problems. Me as a personal trainer,
I identified that people weren't
accountable
to going to the gym.
They didn't know what they'd be doing as
far as following a
workout program,
and they just needed someone to check in
to make sure they ate
less. And I made millions from it.
There were not many good energy drinks
that had
a good nootropic profile.
Made millions from it.
Leveraged that following to sell books
and do book tours off the back of it.
Made millions from it. I got four GCSEs.
I've developed the skill of talking to
camera, but that's about it.
I understand the problems
that people face.
I help them with those problems,
and eventually they go,
"I should probably stick
around to watch this guy's stuff because
he could solve my problems." And then very
simply, I realize that
if I can solve 100 people's problems
and 100 people follow,
maybe three of them might end up doing
business with me.
And then from a numbers game,
you just work backwards.
That might seem reductive,
but I come from a background of
door-to-door sales,
where I used to work for NPower.
My postcode was GL1, which
was Gloucester in the
UK. And during winter,
I used to walk around knocking on people's
doors trying to
sell them gas and electric
when they already had gas and electric.
They just used British Gas,
and I wanted to convert them to NPower.
My average statistics over the four-month
stint that I did that winter was if I
knocked on 100 doors, I got one sale.
And when you looked at my commission
structure, which was pretty poor, and my
£12,000 basic salary.
When it came into the world of personal
training, where I
only had to talk to maybe 50 people to get
a client, that would be recurring
revenue of thousands of pounds a year.
It's like, "Wow, this is easy." Then
when it came to the world of online social
media, what? You're telling me
that I just need to post one video a day,
and
in a few years,
I could have a following
that could support me and my family and my
travel and all of my holidays
and everything else in between?
This is so easy.
I haven't even got to leave the house.
Right now,
I'm only about 400 meters away from my
house.
My biggest concern in life,
if I'm completely honest, is
that the Porsche 911 GT3
outside doesn't get warm.
I don't leave the postcode
that often because everything
is so close. Unfortunately, I believe
that we are gaslit into life.
It's like, go to school, work hard,
don't get in trouble,
then go to university.
Oh, that looks expensive,
but you might get a better job.
But you very rarely do get a better job.
Then you come out of university
and you need to get a job because now
you've got
student debt that you need to pay off.
And you're kind of there thinking, "Huh,
that was kind of a lot of money and I
didn't really learn that much,
but I did have a lot of nights out."
And then you
start a job and you're kind of not really
enjoying it and being like, "Oh, it's
because I'm 21. No one else
is enjoying it.
This must just be part of being young."
And then you kind of think, "Oh, maybe I'm
not supposed to enjoy my job.
I'm just supposed to do my job so I can
pay off my
student loan and my rent
and maybe go to Ibiza for one week each
year." And then you're looking around at
people with nice cars and you think, "Oh,
they must be a managing director,
and maybe if I worked here for 25 to 30
years, I could maybe get promoted to
that one day." Truth is, the majority of
people that drive nice cars,
live in big houses,
and have nice things are business
owners. They have their own business.
And often they do things they really
enjoy.
Like me, I love making these videos.
The fact that I get to call this a job,
fantastic.
I don't get paid from YouTube to do it.
I haven't even got monetization turned on,
like I said before.
Fact of the matter is,
if I turn up here daily
and just give you good little bits
of nuggets and advice to help you see the
world differently and get you to maybe
pull your finger out of your ass
and actually start something, you do well.
So you build the audience.
You build the audience by solving
problems.
You do not take pictures of your lunch.
After a while,
a lot of people will stick around.
Now it's time to solve a problem another
degree closer.
The way I would do that
is with some kind of asset
that takes them away from social
media. Social media is a very busy,
crowded room.
Even right now,
you're probably itching to click away
and watch another video.
Some people have already left the video.
Thank you very much for staying so far.
So for instance,
I could put a link in the description
saying, "Hey, give me your
email address and I'll give you 30 nuggets
of wisdom over the next 30 days." Which
I will, if you click on it. Now,
if you're a business in a lateral industry
to me,
you could just steal that and rip it off.
But you see, I even say
that because I know deep down that even
if you just try and
steal my 30-day email responder,
I would still get a small amount of you
that end
up as clients. It's just the way it works.
I would then run email marketing
campaigns. I'm about to run one now.
It's Christmas Eve today,
and I'm going to put my prices up in the
new year.
So I'm going to engage every single person
on my email list and say, "Hey, beat the
price increase by joining now." That's not
something I want to talk about on social
media.
It's something I just want to hit my email
list with.
Maybe on the 2nd of January,
I might be feeling rather generous
and I might say,
"Hey guys,
I haven't put the prices up yet.
You've got 48 hours to join." I might even
push it back to the 14th of
January. That's not a promise.
Because I know that a lot of people seem
to think
that January, everyone's going to be like,
"New year, new me, let's go." And then
the 13th of January, they're going to go,
"Wow, I still haven't got anywhere near
the amount of clients
that I wanted." I hit them then,
and I'll even say in that
email, "Hey,
I thought you probably thought you would
have more clients this time
of year.
If you do not start doing things properly
with strategy, you will stay
like this for the rest of the year." Then
probably some people will join.
Then from there,
you just have to have something that
is very good as a product
course, offering, or service.
In the onset,
you don't need to have a fancy app.
People could just hire you,
whether you're a coach, yoga instructor,
jujitsu coach,
whatever it is.
Then you could build some kind of platform
where you don't have to
repeat yourself so much.
That's what I'd recommend.
Because when you do give people your time
on calls helping people, as a personal
trainer,
after doing thousand of hours on the gym
floor, I realized, "Hold on,
let's record these videos so that
when people ask me,
I can just send them to the
resource." After you do
that for enough time, you have a course.
Then with a course, like my mentorship,
you then create a community, and I
actually stay in the community on a daily
basis so that I can know what to add to
the course. Then over time,
I build out the course to become better
and better and
better and better so there are less
and less and less questions in the
community.
And in fact,
the majority of the questions now I'm
like, "There's a video for
that." And then if someone asks me
something I haven't made a video for,
I can go
away and make the video.
Suddenly you have an amazing course
that you can sell
people. With personal training,
we created a fitness app,
we hired other coaches.
We wrote the books, we made audiobooks.
We then did in-person live events where
you could come to the event.
It's like a TED Talk with fingering jokes.
But if you want to break free from the
trap of average, from the dangers of
average, you need to start now. This
is my advice to you for 2025.
Fuck it, for whenever.
You're probably paralyzed with the doubt
of, "Oh, I'm not
good enough.
I can't do it." Whatever it is.
I don't give a shit.
You need to make 100 videos,
100 pieces of content as fast as you can,
and I think
you should do them daily.
I didn't say each one had to be a fucking
"Oppenheimer,"
but you need to put one out,
whether it's screenshotting a tweet,
whether it's
doing a carousel post,
whether it's doing a little video,
even talking to camera.
Yes,
I would like it to be filmed on a
high-quality camera, sure.
But even if it's you just talking to
camera, letting people know
that you're here
to solve their problems, that
is going to be fine, I'm sure.
But even if it's you just talking to
camera, letting people know that you're
here to solve their problems, that
is going to be fine, I'm sure.
One piece of content a day the next 100
days.
Because I'll tell you what,
50 days into it, you're going to go,
"Oh my God, I'm a
different person." 75 days into it,
you're going to go, "Oh, I'm embarrassed.
Embarrassed at the level of content I
was putting out before." And by day 100,
you'll probably be finding your feet.
Nothing I have done in my career
is impressive,
but the amount of time I allocated
to each thing before seeking instant
gratification probably is.
I posted on social media for three years
before getting a client, which would be
way quicker for you because we didn't have
a For You page in my day.
I wrote emails for 10 months before anyone
bought anything because I was selling
the wrong thing because I didn't have
anyone on YouTube like this that
was giving
me advice. I fumbled
and stumbled my way through so many
things, and now I just
give you the advice
that I wish I had before.
This is what the books are, actually,
if you think about it.
So I was a fat kid,
didn't really know how to lose fat.
Used to ask the dinner ladies what
was fattening.
So then went through a journey of just
trying to be a little bit more buff and a
little bit leaner so
that my girlfriends could get hotter.
Then experienced a little bit of success
and realized being happy is probably the
best currency that you need.
Having a Porsche helps.
So this is navigating some of the
self-help content
that I used to go through over
the years.
I'm going to sound like a dickhead for
saying this, though.
No one out there making 100 grand a month
needs a self-help book, I'll tell you
that. So up until 100K a month,
read these, but when you're there,
you won't give a
shit about what someone puts in a book.
And then this one was
that a lot of people seemed to think I
was a confident
person. I disagree.
I wouldn't say I'm that confident.
Just whenever the path of action presents
itself, I take it.
More of an opportunist than a confident
person. You got two paths in life.
You can either do the thing
or not do the thing.
If you don't do the thing every time the
opportunity presents itself, you need an
excuse to help you sleep at night.
And usually, "Oh, I'm just not a confident
person." So is that.
But every time you have an idea,
if you make it a piece of
content,
every time you see someone attractive
and you ask them for their number,
every time there's a sniff of an
opportunity for a job
and you put yourself out
there, in enough time,
people will turn around and go, "Wow,
you're a bit of a
confident person." It's not confidence,
it's action.
Please do not settle for average because
there are lots of things you should want
to do in your life, and
if you do it averagely,
you'll probably run out of time.
You'll definitely run out of time.
And your only way out will be buying the
lottery.
YouTube is very smart by going
and it's probably recommended a video here
that you
watch from my channel,
so please go ahead and watch
that because I think it could
be of value. Merry Christmas.